we
are discussing our foundational
documents
whatever week that is of this
so we left off last time so i don't want
to read what we were
proposals and initiation mythologies and
also
if we want to put it on the screen that
would also probably be helpful
i can read this part but we should
probably have it on the screen first
right
and mine doesn't work well for the
screen sharing because again can't do
the
scrolling properly with my current here
awesome so there's this part here
proposals are initiated when at least
two pcic holders are present in an
interactive video meeting
proposals are iterated when at least two
pcic holders are present in an
interactive video meeting
and then at least 75 percent of pcic
holders must be present to come to a
consensus on a
resolution and with no holders blocking
upon positive resolution all details of
the initiation and iteration are
recorded
along with the details of the final
proposal details should include who
initiated the proposal the iterations
and the participated in the resolution
i think we also said that um that sounds
like we have to also put in the
initiation the iteration which makes
sense
but that the like resolution
is the is the part that we need to
record
right so external
jurisdiction keep trying to scroll along
the
document itself the other part right and
should this break
does that be and who participated in the
resolution
yeah that would make sense
participated and then instead of
interactive video meeting do we want to
say board meeting
because i mean theoretically it could be
audio and i'm not sure that we want to
do it outside of the board meeting
because if people are trying to follow
it it might be weird to like
do it in a project you know round table
or something for together tech it seems
like it should be fairly consistent i
think
and i think this is what we had a
20-minute conversation about last week
so i was looking to see if we had
homework
about yeah we can put that in there
because it's it's
like we did say you can come up with and
iterate anything in any medium where
there's any two of us basically even one
of us really but
two for this particular to verbalize it
to somebody else
um but in order for it to be resolved
you'd have to bring it to a board
meeting and say what
what are the what your initiation is and
then the iteration process anyway at
which time
we'd also be doing iterations and then
we would come to a resolution so
i think putting it in the board meeting
makes sense and then we'll just
okay any other thoughts
i know you weren't here last week i
don't know if you had a chance to watch
it or if you're
uh no it all sounds good
i would um one thing i would add to it
is
when i was reading about uh
other styles of proposals
and initiations of proposals um
there was something about i think it was
in a french
aec like something to do with energy
very big company and they tried uh
something non-standard uh for a while
um and they had this system where
um as far as i recall
there was no need for the proposal to be
uh initiated in any other way
than someone just stating i want to do
this and this
and it would by default
go through unless someone objected and
said
um okay this is not i don't know good
enough or
this is this is not good in general but
otherwise
uh proposals did not need any special
or other um like acknowledgement from
everyone or voting or anything like that
it looks like a speed um a fast track
of ideas and fast track of
initiations of execution of
some proposal be it a very small one or
even
like very big one and it would be
something like
i am going to do this and this and
unless someone says
otherwise i am just going to do this so
that's one comment and do we know how
that worked for them
yes it worked good
okay weren't there any like case studies
or you know [ __ ] like how things change
um the case one case study uh i read
about was in the book
um
i quoted it a couple of times before um
inventing work investing organizations
something like that and one example was
setting up a power plant in some like
other country
and it was a literally very big
proposal and someone uh just came up
with this
and said okay i'm going to allocate this
much resources
because it was possible and uh just
built a power plant in
like other country and it worked out
well
so uh from a very small scale to very
big scale
it is possible such a way as as possible
that's just a comment i don't mean
to are there any examples of like how it
changed them though because it sounds
like
companies do that sort of companies
could build power plants in other
countries
even if you voted on it normally so i'm
not sure what the difference like i'm
i'm not did disagreeing i'm just
wondering if there was some sort of a
hey we were getting
you know ham strung up or we were
getting you know we couldn't pass
anything and then we made this change
and all of a sudden we started seeing
good changes
coming through uh no it was like a
normal way of doing stuff in that in
that company
for a while for a couple of years and
the difference was
normally when you um in a company when
you
propose to allocate one percent of all
resources to do something
um new uh what you need is go to
the upper management and get approvals
and
get some people to vote on it and
pass the proposal and you know the
lengthy process
of uh making ideas uh
executable and the difference is
uh in case of this company it was just
as simple as okay i think it's a good
idea
and no one objected
oh no there were some strong objections
i don't remember
my point was that fast tracking of ideas
is also possible and
apparently in some cases it's known to
be working well or well enough and it's
a side comment to this
uh just wanted to be you know um
i just wanted to talk about it okay
well you pissed bentley off and he went
away so i don't think
i think i like that idea i think it
brings it in the holocracy
um governance management to it the issue
is with holocracy is we don't have the
technology to be able to actually
implement it
we have these one-hour conversations and
i think we already
are doing what you suggest like we're
running with our own ideas and i think
we also
have given each other a lot of
permission to just even if it's with
together tech right even if it's with
the facebook group
like you know our shared resources do
what you want
right like try it if it's safe enough
now don't cancel the facebook group
whatever you wanted to try in there the
worst that happens is like
maybe we don't do that right like maybe
we don't post about our individual
projects more than other
you know we post them on here and we do
like we've
figured out the com the conflict
resolution feels like even the wrong
word it hasn't even developed a conflict
but
that that would work if we had other
infrastructure and if together tech was
doing other things right like adriel
doesn't need to come and ask for what
we're doing with wikilection he's just
running with it god knows i'm running
with all of my stuff but if it was
together
tech specifically
i think if we could put it in writing a
certain amount of that
is is welcome and allowed and then also
but we'll get to the next meeting right
like like hey i iterated i did the
initiation the iteration and the
resolution all on my own
and but it's not in the meeting minutes
right like it's not there yet
one uh specific thing about it is
um not about just going ahead and doing
something
and then reporting that oh i just
allocated 50
of resources to buying um
something and then everyone goes uh
it wasn't a good idea it was something
um it's not about
i want to do this because i it's a it's
going public with the idea i want to do
this because
uh i think it would be good to do this
and this and this
and unless some someone objects
i'm going to just do it but uh
first information and then execution
this way
uh it gives everyone a chance to
voice concerns and possibly improve on
the idea or say that the idea
is dumb and just don't do it
i mean the two sound like after being
implemented the end result would be
extremely similar right because like
you'd still have to pitch it to council
you'd still have to have quorum you
still have to have
all these things but it's just sort of
what the default
setting is it sounds like we're saying
we're going to default to saying yes
but then all it takes is one person to
say actually no and then oh okay
no i also think we don't right now
we don't have shared like we don't have
money that are resources right so no
one's saying hey i'm gonna use this
this um scarce resource in order to go
and make a decision where instead our
time is our scarce resource and of
course we're gonna choose where we spend
that
if i'm making it you know i'm gonna make
i'm gonna i'm gonna make a nuclear
reactor no like no one should trust me
to do that if i was allocated those
funds
that would be a disaster so like there's
a certain amount
of like expertise that's involved and
also like yeah go
run with it unless you need me right
like unless you need our shared
resources
which when we have you know what i mean
you're not spending my time
and you're not spending our money and so
yeah run with it and then if you're
able to give us more time and resources
right like
it's when we're giving each other
homework right or we're choosing a
product and saying
and i need other people to come and be
part of this um
that that
we would both if we had the software
that would be a great thing to do
because we'd have those shared resources
let's say we have ten thousand dollars
there
and someone has one idea that's gonna
cost 500 right that that becomes like a
i feel like the amount of resources that
are in there right like you can
try and experiment with let's say one
percent of the pool but you can't you
know whatever that percentage is right
but not
with a hundred percent of the pool not
with
fifty percent of the pool the number of
people involved is the number of people
have to agree
sorry but it still has to be approved so
it's not like you can just take the one
percent or 50 percent 100
and go off and do it and come back and
say sorry guys i messed up i just spent
a lot of money
peace them out they still have to say
hey
you know people in the council i want to
go spend 10 of our
our resources on opening up a power
plant
if we all agree then we don't say
anything and if we don't agree
then we say wait hold up you know and
then voice our concerns right
okay yeah the silent approval of um
is that correct because you like yes
yeah yeah yeah
but uh generally that's the idea to
first state
the the idea is and i'm going to do this
and this and allocate this
much this many resources and then
um the default is yeah go ahead
and um objections happen
um like between
the idea is voiced and the idea is
executed
so yeah it's just uh
the idea goes through unless someone
says something
so i mean
heard like
the wiki election side of me is kicking
in and i'm wondering if you err
on the side of saying yes and then you
know if we're
saying how people voted and you didn't
vote yes but you also didn't vote no and
the thing happens and
you know doesn't do well then that kind
of
to me in a way gives council members
like if the
default is yes and unless you come up
with a really good idea not to
or a good reason not to then that seems
to sort of give
uh a reason for saying like oh yeah i i
voted for but i wasn't paying that close
of
attention as opposed to if you vote yes
for something
then you better know what you're doing
because you you just actually voted as
opposed to
if you vote no like it's i guess the
um assumption of moving forward versus
the assumption of we're not going to do
anything unless we all agree
does that make sense yes it makes sense
i think that could be solved with um
something um okay
a system that allows
for the ideas to be like read up and
presented
and uh some ideas uh
that have bigger bigger scope and
need more time resources and everything
they are more visible than others
something
software software helps
to see what ideas are potentially
[Music]
what ideas are bigger what ideas need
closer look
and more attention from people who can
say
no in a meaningful way and just from
people who can
actually stop the idea from um being
executed uh
yes okay i know this is taking us like
weeks to go through this document but i
do find this process
even if we never get any like this is a
powerful process for us to talk about
these things and um so part so
the iterative process of the iteration
process is actually the part
that is because it's like if i have an
if i initiate an idea all on my own
i'm i don't like that means um i'm
initiated an idl on my own
and then i have an iteration i'm saying
i want permission to go with this
iteration
and no one is and uh how about you go
with this iteration in this iteration in
this iteration
well no because it's my iteration right
if we're
doing the iteration then all of those
iterations and voting on the best one
and and
doing pros and cons and deciding on the
best and going through 75
makes sense but if i'm coming with my
iteration and somebody else
is giving me that homework and being
like you could you need to
iterate it in this way that's somewhat
where the conflict comes in because
they're not like if i'm if it's just my
resources my time
that i get to choose anyway and i'm just
telling you what i'm doing with it if
it's our time
or our resources that i'm using but i'm
but it's my vision that's kind of where
it's like okay well if you're gonna just
say no
do you have a better option or no your
gnome might just be like no i'm not
gonna
you i don't agree that ten percent of
our money is going to go there because i
don't think it's a good return on
investment
like there's a i will say go
good go ahead so i was just going to say
that it's a very good point about uh
allocating someone else's time
uh i think the general idea here is that
um when an idea is presented
it should not require uh
someone specific
time uh to be allocated so it's very
different from the usual
style of doing things like uh i am the
boss so i have this idea and i allocate
you
you and you and just all the team to
do my idea because i think it's good the
difference is
i have the idea and i if i need more
people
i pitch the ideas and i present it in
such a way
that people want to come in and
do the work because they think and
they feel like this is a very good idea
indeed and they want to participate
so uh the idea can be executed and you
know come to life
i feel like there's something here
that's fixing all of game b because
it's like this is like this is what
together tech is right we all brought
our projects to this
and we're working on our own we're not
able to work but there's
something very powerful here that this
iteration so i come to it with an idea
right this is my baby here's where i'm
i'm willing for it to be changed and
here's where i'm not willing for it to
be changed otherwise it's not going to
be my vision anymore
someone else is like well actually that
i would work on your project
if it was x y and not z and then it's up
to us to somewhat negotiate
what that iteration looks like that
would bring in the most people that i'm
as the
idea holder would feel comfortable with
and i'm able to veto it at any point be
like actually no
and they're able to take it and run with
it if i've kind of outbeated myself
that there's something here that kind of
is like can you present your idea well
enough that people are coming on board
with you have enough people to make it
viable
because that's also part of it right if
some idea needs 10 people to be viable
but you only have two
it's not viable right and there's
something here yeah it's like presenting
this is my idea this is my baby and
obviously this is the most beautiful
baby in the world
um it's just convincing other people
that it is indeed the most
babies
and not yours
um when you had said that like if you're
spending your own time
you know and resources and stuff like
that is that under the
together tech umbrella or is that under
like your own project
[Music]
so yeah i've been out on this for a
while so i apologize but
but yeah i think this deciding process
is just for the shared resources listed
so this isn't even like
you know this doesn't have anything to
do with ideas and stuff like that i mean
we
need to talk about all that but this
document is just about those shared
resources
i just wanted to make a side comment to
this and not meant to take
20 minutes of our time to discuss it uh
so yeah definitely that's it i think
that this is taking weeks is actually
very powerful because
yes this is like to see something of
this level
with like the brett weinsteins and like
get in the weeds super like
because this is about as in the weeds as
you can get
actually trying to build a foundational
document for like what kind of
organization would actually work for all
of us
um but one of the things to think about
what
if if we're saying that the whole point
of all this is how we we manage our
assets
one of the things that's not an asset
here which technically is in like the
business world
is the brand is that you know when
people think of together tech
what do they th did they think of which
i'm sure
when i say that a bunch of people are
like that sounds like game a
supportive yes but most tech brands
should go under assets i think you're
right i think that makes total sense
yeah i thought we put that there last
time but i guess it didn't get
transferred over
and it'll be about it's like game b the
brand of game b
is very nebulous and chaotic and no one
can kind of co-opt it because it's like
that it's like i can't come and be like
i can tell you i know how to make game b
but i know that you know anything that's
not quite the same as no this is the
only game b that can exist and it's like
if you're working as
together tech that's under the brand
together tech
but no like wiki election and reason
score
and solution reason isn't under together
tech even though it is right like
it can [ __ ] up and not show negatively
on the brand on together
yeah yeah and as we get more projects
guaranteed some of them will [ __ ] up
like that's
i hope so yeah exactly because otherwise
what are we even doing
um but i i guess so to tie that back to
the earlier statement of like
if you're trying to do something under
the together tech brand
and you're using your own time your own
resources your own this i think that
still gets voted on at least to start
with
because you're doing it under the the
brand so the question is does that fit
under the
the together tech brand or can you go
off on your own and do it as
your own project right like i'm not
going to ask the group what to do with
wiki election or conferrati
because those are my projects if i
wanted to pitch something new you guys
are like that doesn't sound like
together tech
i can either drop it or start up another
project of my own
that's not under together tech so it
could be a project but it
it's not under the together tech brand
so i think that's
something to consider and then over time
we'll have to
start to come up with some sort of i
don't know milestones or things to watch
out for where we're like okay it's time
to change this
we're getting really top heavy we have
to meet about everything maybe
it's time to start you know identifying
like okay you don't have to ask about
these things or you just have to ask a
certain person or a certain group
i don't know how to put it in writing
but i feel like what we like raymond
says to do we're already doing and we
kind of we already
are both i feel permission to run with
ideas and then bring and be like by the
way that's what i did
and with this if that ever happens
there's also the
maybe you shouldn't have done that right
like it works both ways both
to feel like you have permission to try
things which means they might go wrong
and you might
well next time we're not going to have
it go that way and
because the other option is of course we
have to run everything through here i
have an id on a saturday and then we're
not meeting until next friday
and it's like i like to run with things
right away that there's like
i think we are giving each other
permission to try things especially
since there aren't
monetary shared assets yet um that is a
way
that we could maybe play with this is we
don't yet have resort
don't yet have monetary resources and
we're not
going to necessarily have them anytime
soon but
if we were right if we were like hey how
about we each put 10 bucks a month into
a pool
um that would be a proposal and then if
someone's iterations like actually i
only want to put 10 dollars in every
quarter
actually i want to put 20 in that like
that is an actual and then it would be
like how to spend those funds when
they're there
that part of this is we don't have the
asset so getting to that point
would need to go through this process i
don't know if i'm really explaining what
i'm trying to explain in my head
it's coming out right but like like
anything that's going to be generating
assets to add to this list is going to
have to go through the proposal system
that's what i heard
that might be just i was thinking it
might be like
although once we're ready to get
resources it's gonna have to go through
this but also going through like a play
version of that right like i would
i would be like i had this great idea
everyone involved in together tech's
gonna put 50 bucks a month towards it
i've initiated between this and next
time right and i cog and you're like
well wait no that's why 50 bucks you're
willing to put yours in
okay so and then we do then it starts
being the iterative process
right where it's like how about not 50
how about not once a month how about not
to
reach this threshold right that there's
still that
um yeah this is so something we'll have
to go through and it's something sooner
rather than later that will
i mean when i think about proposals i
kind of think of it a bit like
legislation where outside of you know
actually voting on it and having a
session
you can work with either you know you
can work on your own or you can go and
work with others
to like author a bill and then get
sponsors and then once you have all of
the required things
you pitch it to everyone else um
i think like i'm not saying that we need
to be that hard and fast about it
but the basic idea of like
when you bring it to to council with the
intention of
you know let's vote on this that's kind
of you're technically starting at
initiation if you just did a killer job
and you had you know all your ducks in a
row and every single thing was done
and we all look at the proposal and say
that's great
let's do it you could skip over
iteration
that wouldn't normally happen i wouldn't
think but uh
you know that theoretically could happen
but you know you could just say
in a session hey i have an idea how
about this that could be an
initiation it could just be pitching an
idea in this meeting and then we can
talk about it
at a certain point you know or i guess
we actually only document it at the
resolution so that's fine
because then you can talk about it if it
falls away
fine if somebody won't want to keep
working on it
because like that sort of sparked an
idea and it didn't quite get approved in
the meeting but like
oh okay yeah rep you know if it seemed
to jive with me
and red x then we can meet either you
know talk about it during it
most likely we meet afterwards have our
own discussion build it out you know
hopefully build some kind of specs or a
proposal around it
and then eventually officially come to
the board and say hey
here's this idea that we've been working
on what does everyone think
does that make sense it strikes me as
something
very important to compare proposals to
legit legislation
the most basic level i do want to make
sure that it doesn't emulate legislation
too exactly because
we know there's a ton of issues there
but the basic idea of it sort of being
you got a bunch of work done beforehand
to try to make it sort of passable on
the
the first round and when things get
bigger
you you may even end up with things like
sponsorship
where it's like okay before you you know
spend 20 minutes of everyone's time in a
board meeting talking about it
find one other council member to talk
about it and get buy-in and then cool
we'll talk about it and i'm not saying
that we do that yet because there's four
of us
um but you know if there ends up being
15 or 20 of us
probably good to have some sort of a no
you can't all just throw any ideas
whenever
you know you have to have it at least x
level and
you have to have one other person sign
on for it
before we spend people's time and again
that's down the road
which will end up i think with all of
this
it's going to be a very different battle
to sort of have a council have a board
with four people versus 10 or 20.
and also do we want to max size for
board because i mean if we
bring on every project and every this
like theoretically you could end up with
a board of like
100 people that seems unwieldy
oh no i guess we can cross that bridge
when we come to it
the roman army was organized in uh
like 10 100 and it was a very
um the structure was
uh i think designed to actually yeah
counter uh weight the
uh unwillingness of tons of people
now was that still fairly top down like
was it
yeah you know the top ten give
instructions to
you know to their underlying and then
those people give instructions to their
100 and those people give instructions
to their thousand
or were you know a certain group if you
have a unit of 100
your your own unit go and do your own
thing i assume it's the first because
it's the army
now we now we have the technology to uh
make something much more smarter and uh
well
i mean obviously uh
small units of just a few people who can
um
quickly work together on one
specific thing as the
future and then connecting the small
units
uh into one bigger hole with a software
system
obviously this is what we can do and
this is also the future uh it's a
fractal dao
thing again um yes
which army are you talking about radic
army
the roman army like the plan yes ancient
times
like technology and i was like wait who
has that
i i don't know it's a i don't know why i
heard about
the roman army but what i thought about
this
small units um that have
each unit has one person who goes up the
like command chain and
form a unit that is high level up on
on the yeah sorry um
but back to the original thought the
proposal creating a proposal
is as creating kind of a law
uh and i don't know why it seems
important
it's maybe it's because it has certain
weight and not process
but i mean i think in a way
with legislation it kind of i think has
the opposite
effect because in legislation like
something is legal unless it's not
right it's not like who who said you
could do that that's not how laws work
we passed laws to say you can't do that
okay now you can't everything else is
still open
the board is kind of the reverse we're
saying hey here's our vision here's our
mission here's all this stuff
everything should be going in this
direction we want to catalog as much in
sort of both
directions in theory if it's not stated
then it's kind of not allowed
or unless like it you know if the dog if
the
current documentation or procedures or
whatever if they cover it
then you follow what they say things get
murky if
there's no rule surrounding it and then
you would try to use the mission and
vision to say like oh okay
what choice could we we make here in
alignment with our mission and vision
okay this is that
yeah that makes sense sort of what your
concerns were or is it something totally
different
no i'm not concerned i'm just like
there's
something sounds important there in that
connection of
uh i mean what you said is of course
totally true
it's just
i i don't know what i'm thinking about
totally
but it's something very philosophical i
think and uh
that's why i get it you know i get those
same things where i'm like there's
something here there's something that my
brain is like pay attention
usually it's because there's a problem
but it can't identify what it is yet
they're like keep thinking because
there's something in there that like
there's something that's coming up for
me i don't know if it'll help or hinder
so feel
free to throw it away but there's
something like we talked about that we
have our own projects
and then we under and then there's the
together tech umbrella there's also like
our own individual lives
and whatever we're creating like how i
don't want anything that's a hierarchy
over my life
right and i think there's something in
like an iteration an initiation process
that's like this whether it's a leak
whether we state what you can do and you
can't do anything else or we say what
you can't do and you can do everything
else
is somewhat in that same realm of like
we have laws you can't murder each other
you have to but outside of that
everything that's not explicit should be
allowed
right like it's like all of the libya
and his neurodiverse person a very
neurotypical world is like wait
why why do you like that's common sense
and everyone should just know this there
should be nothing
that sits in that realm because we're
not all able to sit in that realm but
have permission to play and have
permission to use the resources have
permission to initiate and iterate
and even resolve in your own life and in
your own projects but then we also have
a process of like oops that went wrong
oops actually we don't like people to
come around and like there's something
in that the realm is the magic word here
uh laws and proposals are
ways to map the territory on which we
exist kind of that's the proposal it's
like
you know in strategy games
you have the fog of war uh kind of thing
that you just discovered the territory
by sending your uh
uh troops or whatever uh to go
in a direction and then discover stuff
and proposals seem
kind of similar you just
you define and describe a piece of
reality that you want to happen
and okay this is feels philosophical
but there's something to it definitely i
mean to be fair i think this entire
thing is kind of philosophical
yeah yes yes because i was thinking like
when you mentioned the first
the um example of the
nuclear reactor right that they and it's
like okay i'm the person who wants to
create a nuclear reactor and i want it
to be in vancouver because it's where i
live and i want to be the one running it
that's very different someone comes up
with the iteration process it's like
actually i think it should be in toronto
you just messed up everything right like
it's like why because i'm in toronto and
i want to do it well that's
like that there's um
the initiation iteration process the
iteration the person who brings the
initiation has a reason for initiating
that
and the iterations can um support that
i could iterate all day bring me in
bring me in a fully formed idea and i'll
give you a million different iterations
for
it as well as what could go wrong with
them and that's not helpful
most of the time right like it's not
helpful unless it is to say hey
like the location is it is an iteration
right the amount of money who's in
charge of that
that nuclear plant is an iteration how
much output it's putting in why we're
even doing it
all of their forms of iteration there's
the initiation the iteration the
resolution is like right
and we're giving you an okay to go build
it is that
does it need to go through the process
or can i just go and build one unless no
one says no
um with a nuclear plan i feel like i
want people to say no
with with you know what i mean i want to
run this ad campaign or i want this it's
like
go try it until it especially we don't
have those shared resources
right which i think the whole like go
and try it and do this that
might end up being a part of like kind
of a regular part of the initiation and
iteration is like that sounds
interesting
we don't know enough yet what can we
test to learn more so that with this
you know with the main proposal we
aren't sure so let's have like
a sub-proposal where we test things out
and learn more and then say okay great
we just learned this
we just learned that we don't want a
reactor here or we do
um and i do think when it comes to the
iteration
things like i want it here because i
live here that would be a reason for you
to vote but for no one else
and if everyone only wants it for
themselves that's where things fall
apart quickly
which they should at that point because
you know if your only reason to have it
in vancouver is because you want it to
be close and someone else
wants in toronto because it's close to
them that's equal
that's for the group and i'm the one who
brought the proposal right so i'm the
one who's i think it matters even a
little bit
to the overall group if you want to do
it yourself outside of together tech no
one's stopping you yeah
yeah and but that is the so if i'm like
like right now while i'm i'm creating
the uh the meta learning magic
there's part of me that's like okay this
needs to work for everyone i'm like [ __ ]
that no it doesn't have to work for me
because i'm the main person here i'm the
one who has the idea i know where this
is going if it doesn't work for me it
doesn't work for anyone
if someone else was like actually i
think we should do x y and z because
that'll work for me i actually trump
them in that
because it needs to work for me and
that's what like if i'm the one who's
creating the nuclear power plant
there's a reason because i'm the nuclear
power expert you're
saying you're voting to move me to
toronto is what i'm saying
so because i'm the one who's going to be
running the nuclear plant now if someone
else is like i live in toronto i could
run it
that's a different story but like it's
my life you're voting on
so yeah you might want it in toronto
because you don't want it in vancouver
because you don't want it
sorry to be clear we are never voting on
someone's life
we're voting on a project if you choose
to participate and
you know we might take you know we we we
might weigh into consideration where do
all of our experts live
who's willing to move blah blah blah
okay here are our sites that we've set
our potential
now let's talk about the pros and cons
for each and down
yeah um but i think and this sounds like
an important
distinction is if it's something like
this yours and you want to have full
control over it
it's your project and then yes
absolutely like i'm fully i
think that for the most part i'm
skeptical about the whole crowd run
things i i think no matter what we have
to end up there i just don't think that
we have seen a really good world-class
version of it yet
and we're gonna need a bunch of
iterations of that
and so it's that's one of the things
that together tech is testing
is that group decision making as many of
us have to buy in as possible etc
but if you're an expert and you want to
go and do it yourself that becomes a
project like
reason score or wiki election or
whatever where you own it it's yours
you you you run it and personally that's
how
i think those projects will be more
successful until we get the group thing
absolutely nailed down yeah that is like
literally
the meat of what we are discussing right
now is like this because there's there's
always the flip side of like okay i like
together tech
the name anyway was my baby and then now
it's our baby
and when i come up with a new idea i
don't have it necessarily under the
together tech umbrella it's
it's side part of that is because i
don't
know if it's allowed here right like
there's a certain amount of like okay
it's my
solution racing's my project i would
love other people to run with it but
they're not so like how do i
how do i create this what am i trying to
get to here
i don't know it went away it sounds like
the the question is
how and when does a project transition
from being yours to being like
sort of a group right i
remembered it unevaporated so it's if as
an
individual i can i can create as a loner
and i would love to create as a group
the group part is harder
but because i can't do that yet
everything becomes a solo project
starting from scratch right like it's
like oh and i think this is the crux of
the game be way too many projects and
not enough people
it's like everyone kind of wants to
start from scratch and everyone wants to
have their ideas integrated and
like and so it's partly having this
process
of hey you can run with it
and we'll just like later on we might
take you out of together tech but
otherwise like giving people permission
to be
individuals work with what they can and
you can't really [ __ ] it up because
we're saying we're allowing you to have
that so the worst you can do
is [ __ ] up to the point we need a new
rule right which is like you didn't
break it because it wasn't there before
i think right
but it's allowed yes going back
to like the overall mission and vision
things like building a reactor
from what i understand that would be a
project and if it like that
budget outside of together check that
one or you know agar free
owns but that's their project and then
if we say hey does that meet our
criteria you know to be
um you know a project that has long-term
benefits to most beings
if it passes that great come on board we
don't own your project we're just going
to offer you resources to help you
get it to where it needs to be and then
in you know a later state
when we've got a bunch of people and
possibly some resources did
they talk about a small pivot where it's
like hey should we look at owning some
of these
because some of these look for something
like wiki election i don't want to own
that forever
if it takes off i want like a group
thing to own
i just want to make sure that it's run
properly and i think a lot of projects
are probably
like that where you don't want to be the
linchpin
for you know the entire time it exists
and what happens after you die and that
kind of thing yeah and we have to deal
with wikileaks in 10 years from now and
i don't mean wiki election 10 years from
now i mean whatever 10 years from now is
equivalent quick election is because if
the new adrenal has to hold it
and take that risk that's the problem
that we need to solve
taking the risk and taking the reins and
doing all of that
whereas if we have a way that anyone
with a new idea can get a group of
people together get funding if it's a
good enough idea together
then no you don't hold it from day one
but you might be able to run with it
right you might be able to
sorry
this touches um on a very
um i don't think we discussed
one point here but the question is at
what point
um where is the point where
uh a project that is mine becomes
uh shared and what gives other people
who joined
um the right
to vote no on
how i see the direction of the project
uh should be you know
uh i start for example i start one
um like idea i put in a proposal and
that
pass and people join me so what gives
when people start getting the right to
um say
uh to the original um author of the
project
that the direction is wrong and then and
that the project
needs to steer in like another direction
honestly convention of ownership what is
the question
when you sell it the
the whole idea is that to get the tech
at least for the next you know
10 years probably is operating in the
game a world and operates based on all
the laws as they exist
which you know there's ownership like
there's laws around a lot of stuff so i
think
the idea is together tech starts off
just being you know a community to sort
of help
these projects to take off at a certain
point the goal is for it to start to get
its own resources
once that happens at a certain point it
will want to actually start
being able to buy things right like if
you put in a bunch of your own
time and effort and you build out hyper
logos to the point where
you know it's great it's working people
are using it you as a project owner
technically have the option to either
keep it for yourself
sell it to a game a company or sell it
to a game b company
there's probably some other ones i'm
missing but that's the basic idea
you a game a company they own it it's
not yours anymore that's
you know healthy i think there's a
there's a much more nebulous in between
way that we'll probably end up going for
it because that's very obvious right we
sold it it's now
together text when wikilection is bought
by together tech that will be obvious
but there's also
a more nebulous like okay people are on
board with wiki elections not just
adriel so
so adriel gets to decide how to let
people in on that right how to how to be
like how are we
making this go and together tech can
have the software
the hardware to allow for that process
of like hey these people are decision
doing this right and these people are
decision makers and these
that that there does need to be an
obvious process
a not just you know like when you're
dating someone you're like are we
exclusive
like an act like an actual conversation
of like
who's on this who's because i don't
think together tech should own and
operate wiki election at any point
if that doesn't work whereas if we
bought it yes but like
i might have a voting share on wiki
election and be part of that
and not be it of together tech or vice
versa right together tech doesn't
necessarily
wiki election might need its own
governance and then
together tech can vote whether or not
they're they own it
possible but i think that what would be
similar to like
you know a multinational conglomerate
today where they just own a bunch of
things
and in in in the current model it's
entirely for profit that's what would be
changing but the idea is for the most
part the conglomerates leave those
organizations with their own governance
their own boards all that stuff
so they're still like people making
decisions for that organization
but they report to sort of the higher
the higher group
um i think i did leave out what i think
is
a likely in-between step between the
like just helping people move forward
and then buying things
which is having forms of like
certifications
where as we work with the community to
be like hey what does it mean for
company to be trustworthy
or what do you need to you know trust
like a manufacturer or
any of the things that that the
community starts to say hey
let's figure out you know easily which
companies are in
in alignment by having a form of
certification kind of like the
organic one right like this this
conversation in particular
like what hap like the conglomerate in
game a and game b
isn't helpful right now because we don't
know which one of like we don't know
whether it's going to be a conglomerate
and it's going to be under whether we're
going to buy and whether we're going to
do that
that process we each have our vision of
what that might look like in the future
but what we're dealing with is right now
and so i think if we want to bring it
back for the last 10 minutes
to our stewarded assets of the website
of facebook of the brand
um we're going through this iteration
process are we good with the iteration
process when somebody wants to do
something with one of those
assets are we okay they can they can
iterate and and do that on their own
and we'll resolve it and record it when
75 of us say yes and we'll be bringing
them to this board meeting because
that's our current technology
and we do give each other permission to
make mistakes until there's a firm rule
not to so if you do have an idea
tomorrow morning you want to implement
between now and next friday
go ahead we will we will like break this
before we make it and that's fine
right like to be like well wait i know
we gave you permission but yeah just
yeah just messed it all up right like i
like that
with the the added i mean to me obvious
but
it has to fulfill the mission and vision
like if it
if you feel that you can argue that
whatever yo you're like you know you
want to make a change to the facebook
group or a post or
you know do you do something with any of
the the resources
if it isn't in alignment with those two
hard no right and that might be what
comes up when you make a mistake we're
going to be like actually that thing you
posted was not omnipotent it was not
antibiotic even if it's not
a benefit of all beans even if it
technically works as
designed though if it doesn't meet those
it's still kind of a mistake
like it worked but you still shouldn't
have done it because it didn't align
with the mission
and i think those are important
conversations we will have on like
but like every post on our facebook page
is not
you know what i mean like other people
post as well but we are the admins so
maybe
we are seen as more of like other people
posting
in theory are a part of that group right
so those are kind of we don't have
customers but kind of our customers
or our users or our audience or however
you want to say it
so that's those people so for us posting
as together tech
everything should be sort of going
towards our mission and vision
and all those projects so like if you
come with a project like
hey let's build a reactor we look at
this and say i'm not sure how that
you know we'll have your project for
together tech because that itself
doesn't help do this if that project is
going to have long-term benefits to most
beings that might be a project that we
help support
but sort of phase one of together tech
is just is this is
just us you know hopefully providing
some form of guidance
and you know sort of a a community and
then
at some future point in time you know if
we get a big enough audience to start to
actually gain
some monetary assets then we can start
to book great now what do we do with it
and that's a conversation for future us
once we have those resources and stuff
like that
i like the idea of having a rule against
making mistakes
my iterations the exact opposite of that
if you haven't made
several mistakes by the time you've been
here for six months you're out
okay because we haven't made a mistake
we wanted to learn from your mistakes
and you didn't make any so
uh useless exactly
uh should we can you go down adro and um
we'll do
just reread for the uh propose that part
okay
so reports are initiated when at least
two people are present in a board
meeting
proposals are iterated at least two
people are present in a board meeting
that's good too because even if two of
us just show up we can just have a
conversation and you know do what we do
which is create game b
in a very ethereal way instead of
actually concretely
as we're doing next as we're working on
projects which are very concrete
uh at least 75 of pcic holders must be
present
to come to a consensus on a resolution
with no holders blocking
um which is basically you can go with it
unless someone says no in all honesty
it's like but we're gonna actually vote
like someone can block it
no i don't want i'm always voting
nuclear power plants down just so we're
clear
it's never ever happening unless they're
new
the other kind uh this part underneath
this jurisdiction dispute resolution the
whole time this has been here with these
other names i don't know whether
like who added those whether they were
just there already
i think they're part of the template
okay so i don't
know they were just there um initial
team accountability i mean i think that
having a dispute would now that we're
gonna get into this right now four
minutes left but
um a dispute resolution is important and
i think even just putting in we
understand
disputes are gonna happen we will need a
resolution
and i think it kind of needs we need a
dispute to be able to resolve first to
say
hey all right to be clear this mentions
external jurisdiction so i think
when i read that i think of it more like
where are we going to incorporate
that's a part of that conversation
because that you know if we're sued or
we sue someone
where does that lawsuit happen right and
like if we end up having some sort of an
agreement that people sign
okay gotcha gotcha so if like if
wikilection comes on board we have them
sign hey
we're gonna do arbitration instead of
going in this yeah
that that that's my understanding but it
might mean something different but that
like
because this is still you know a game b
you know organization operating in a
game a world and even outside of gaming
just how our governments work which are
still
you know kind of game-made but still um
that's what i think it means
and that does seem important for us
because
you know already in this call we've got
three countries
and in the group overall we have a ton
of countries and so then the
question is like how does that work and
it might just end up being
you know it's based where it's based and
each project has its own thing
and this might not actually be an issue
until we have agreements to sign
until there is something like you're
joining up because right now it seems
all very informal
i'm not sure that we really need to do
that but that's
that's almost certainly something that
raymond should the fact where global
will work to our advantage in that
because i think it's actually really
important
that we put in there that any kind of
distribute that it has to be
a some sort of internal system and not
external
because if we are going to sue each
other yeah who's court and with what and
how
no you agreed to be part of this if the
tension is between our two projects or
between
we're gonna do not consensus whatever i
just said before that the
arbitration and have our own internal
process
and then we have documents that people
have signed there for
you can't say actually i think i will be
better under the court in the united
states or in the court of new zealand
and i'm going to sue you under there
you still can because we can't undo the
law right we can't
um if we did something egregious they
can still do that but they've signed
documents saying right for something
little no you can't go and sue uh sorry
you've signed me or even for something
big it's at least an
arrow and the the quiver on well you
also decided to do this and you skipped
that step
it's not to say that the arbitration
would have been successful
but at the very least start there and
yeah it's to your point it's never
bulletproof you can still
get around things that you've signed
like you know a waiver
doesn't just mean that you can throw all
of your security standards out
of the window you're still expected to
make it be safe you can still be sued
even if you have waivers
same basic idea all right down to the
last couple minutes radical looked like
he had something he wanted to add and
then we'll
close this and continue next week
hopefully with bentley
yeah this uh just two things uh internal
disputes um like the low
weights um disputes
to be resolved within um
like our power to to
solve and then there is always external
um
all those external interfaces to actual
law systems and um
jurisdictions and how to
if we are not able to uh solve our own
problems
within uh together tech uh where do we
go
to what external authority
we consider to be uh
we choose to obey like both
parties that are involved in a dispute
they would need to
agree uh under which jurisdiction they
are going to be
uh told what the resolution actually is
[Music]
and that is it's hard because we're
internal external we're trying to become
like it's it's going to be difficult to
figure that because we want a third
party probably to do it but there is no
third party and yet
there always needs to be so it's almost
like a jury of your peers
it's almost like we need to have like a
jury of other business like
project holders and for both parties to
vote and say yes i'm okay with that
person i think they'll be impartial
and what that like on our r4 we can't do
that right like
two of us are siblings no badly like i
mean you know we're working on different
projects together
but i think we would right now we could
do a third party right we could have
somebody outside of this but in game b
do it but eventually that becomes this
is going to be an important conversation
um which we can continue next time of
course do we want to invite raymond to
the next one or do we think we need
another one to kind of talk about this
jurisdiction resolution
or accountability another one i think so
too
and then he can come and kind of help us
clean this part up his last three when
we kind of work through
yeah i think it's also worth noting that
like i don't think that
the jurisdiction part really comes into
play until we actually have things
signed
because until then like somebody in new
zealand could try and sue me that can
just be like no
and then what are they going to do i'm
not in new zealand i don't have an
organizational entity there
yeah we're just having those
conversations because it doesn't matter
if wikilection gets sued that's
not reason score suing wiki election or
wikileaks
there's a big difference and with how
much we are interweaving our projects
right if like wikilection makes you a
billionaire and
bentley internet has helped but recent
score doesn't go anywhere
there all of those things could come up
and part of it is kind of creating the
um
prenuptial prenuptial before while we're
in love
instead of waiting until the resolution
right like that
and so anyway so no raymond next week
just so i have this for when i rewatch
it next time no raymond next week we're
going to do this one more week we're
here tomorrow for our round tables
and um otherwise we'll be going we'll
look we'll sit with this jurisdiction
dispute resolution
ideas will percolate in all of our
brains and we'll talk about this for one
more week
all right goodbye youtube and face